Richard Henry Lee Papers 1763-1823 Mss.B.L51
American Philosophical Society
- Richard Henry Lee Papers, 1763-1823; 0.5 lin. feet (Box 1)
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 Apr. 22; 4p.; Washington, George
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 May 10; 1p.; Washington, George
    Introducing the Chevalier d'Annemours.
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 May 17; 4p.; Washington, George
    Requests instructions for what to do with so many foreigners appointed by Congress to field officer over native born Americans.
  - ALS to George Washington, 1777 May 22; 2p.; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794
  - ADfS to Patrick Henry, 1777 May; 4p.; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 June 1; 3p.; Washington, George
  - ALS Cy to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 June 15; 4p.; Lee, Arthur, 1740-1792
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 June 26; 2p.; Adams, Samuel
  - ALS Cy to Unidentified recipient, 1777 July 1; 2p.; Chase, Samuel, 1741-1811
  - ALS to Thomas Paine, 1777 July 13; 2p.; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 July 1; 2p.; Paine, Thomas, 1737-1809
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 Aug. 24; 2p.; Wythe, George
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 Sept. 13; 1p.; Pendleton, Edmund, 1721-1803
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 Sept. 16; 1p.; DeKalb, Johann
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 Sept. 23; 2p.; Page, Mann
    News of defeat of Burgoyne at Saratoga.
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 Oct. 11; 1p.; Pendleton, Edmund, 1721-1803
  - ALS Cy to George Pynchon and John Bradford, 1777 Oct. 14; 1p.; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 Oct. 18; 1p.; Wythe, George
  - ADfS to George Wythe, 1777 Oct. 19; 3p.; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794
  - ADfS to United States. Congress, 1777 Oct. 24; 1p.; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 Oct. 27; 2p.; Page, Mann
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 Nov. 5; 3p.; Mifflin, Thomas
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 Nov. 6; 2p.; Wythe, George
  - ALS to Arthur Lee, 1777 Nov. 9; 3p.; Wilkes, John
    "This poor country is fallen into a fatal lethargy, from which all efforts to rouse her seem ineffectual. The single loss of Minorca drove the people of England almost to madness, now thirteen provinces dismembered from the British empire scarcely excite a murmur, except among a very few, who dare to love their country even at this disagreeable period."
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 Nov. 12; 3p.; Mifflin, Thomas
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 Nov. 28; 2p.; Chase, Samuel, 1741-1811
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1777 Dec. 3; 2p.; Lee, William
    Urges enlisting British and German deserters to encourage such behavior.
  - ADfS to Thomas Johnson, 1777 Dec. 13; 2p.; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794
    Complaint about Marylanders trading with British warships.
  - ALS Cy to Thomas Johnson, 1777 Dec. 28; 4p.; Lovell, James, 1737-1814
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, ca.1777; 2p.; Lee, Charles
  - ALS Cy to George Washington, 1778 Jan. 2; 2p.; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794
    Re: British tricks and forgery of "Letters from Washington."
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 Feb. 15; 2p.; Washington, George
    "The enemy are governed by no principles that ought to actuate honest men..."
  - ALS to Arthur Lee, 1778 March 12; 1p.; Windham, W.
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 Apr. 20; 3p.; Adams, Samuel
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 May 23; 3p.; Conway, Thomas, 1733-ca.1800
    Blames a cabal against him for leaving his commission.
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 June 18; 2p.; Henry, Patrick
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 June 23; 1p.; Page, Mann
  - ALS Cy to George Washington, 1778 June 24; 1p.; Lee, Richard Henry, 1732-1794
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 July 2; 2p.; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves, marquis de, 1757-1834
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 July 10; 2p.; Page, John, 1744-1808
    Congratulations on departure of British from Philadelphia.
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 Aug. 1; 1p.; Wythe, George
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 Aug. 10; 4p.; Washington, George
    Re: Col. Spotswood.
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 Aug. 13; 1p.; Pulaski, Kazimierz, 1747-1779
    Seeking Lee's support against false accusations made against Pulaski.
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 Aug. 17; 2p.; DeKalb, Johann
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 Sept. 21; 2p.; Lee, William
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 Sept. 23; 4p.; Gates, Horatio, 1728-1806
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 Sept. 23; 2p.; Washington, George
    Paper money. "The designs of the Enemy, to me, are mysterious -- indeed totally incomprehensible..."
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 Oct. 15; 4p.; Page, John, 1744-1808
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 Oct. 17; 4p.; Lee, William
    Diplomatic efforts in Germany.
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 Nov. 8; 2p.; Whipple, William
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 Dec. 10; 2p.; Lovell, James, 1737-1814
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1778 Dec. 18; 4p.; Lovell, James, 1737-1814
  - Cy to Great Britain. Commissioners, ca.1778; 1p.; [United States. Congress]
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 Jan. 7; 2p.; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves, marquis de, 1757-1834
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 Oct. 7; 3p.; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves, marquis de, 1757-1834
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 March 25; 4p.; McKean, Thomas, 1734-1817
    Political machinations in Congress since Lee's departure and Franklin's against Arthur Lee.
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 April 15; 4p.; Reed, Joseph, 1741-1785
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 April 22; 1p.; Holker, John
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 April 5; 2p.; Holker, John
  - LS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 May 5; 1p.; Washington, George
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 June 13; 3p.; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves, marquis de, 1757-1834
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 June 22; 2p.; Laurens, Henry, 1724-1792
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 June 17; 2p.; Jefferson, Thomas.
    Bibliography
    Printed: Boyd, v.2, 298-299.
    General note
    Film 199 Frame 68
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1780 Aug. 15; 2p.; Lee, William
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 Aug. 17; 4p.; Lovell, James, 1737-1814
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 Aug. 23; 2p.; Whipple, William
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 Aug. 31; 4p.; Laurens, Henry, 1724-1792
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 Sept. 18; 2p.; Whipple, William
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 Sept. 28; 2p.; Laurens, Henry, 1724-1792
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 Oct. 12; 2p.; Laurens, Henry, 1724-1792
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1779 Dec. 13; 1p.; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves, marquis de, 1757-1834
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1780 Aug. 31; 1p.; Lovell, James, 1737-1814
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1781 Jan. 15; 2p.; Adams, Samuel
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1781 Feb. 8; 1p.; DeGrasse, Conte de
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1781 March 10; 3p.; Jefferson, Thomas.
    Re: Steuben and militia.
    Printed: Boyd, v.5, 114-115.
    Film 199 Frame 69
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1781 June 15; 2p.; Weedon, George
    Defences in Virginia.
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1781 Aug. 12; 2p.; Weedon, George
  - ALS to Arthur Lee, 1781 Sept. 4; 2p.; McKean, Thomas, 1734-1817
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1781 Sept. 20; 1p.; Weedon, George
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1781 Oct. 29; 1p.; DeGrasse, Conte de
    In French.
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1783 Sept. 15; 2p.; Whipple, William
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1783 April 4; 3p.; Monroe, James, 1758-1831
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1783 April 17; 2p.; Whipple, William
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1784 June 12; 2p.; Washington, George
    "Unsolicited by, and unknown to Mr. Paine, I take the liberty of hinting the services, and distressed (for so I think it may be called) situation of that Gentleman."
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1784 Oct. 8; 2p.; Florida-Blanca, Conte de
    On verso Richard Henry Lee ALS Cy to Florida Blance, 1785 Oct. 6. Regarding future of Spanish-American relations.
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1784 Dec. 9; 1p.; Adams, Samuel
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1784 Dec. 23; 4p.; Adams, Samuel
    "By God's Blessing on the Councils and the Arms of our Country, we are now ran'k with Nations. May they keep us from exulting beyond Measure! Great Pains are tyet to be taken and much Wisdom is requisite that we may stand as a Nation in a respectable Character. Better it would have been for us to have fallen in our highly famed Struggle for our Rights, or even to have remain'd in our ignoble State of Bondage hoping for better Times, than now to become a contemptible Nation."
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1784 Dec. 14; 4p.; Washington, George
    Re: Treaty of Fort Stanwix. "These people [the Iroquois] have given I think all that the United States could reasonably have asked of them -- more perhaps than the state of New York conceive ought to have been required from them, by any other than their own Legislature."
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1785 Feb. 8; 8p.; Washington, George
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1785 Feb. 28; 1p.; Pendleton, Edmund, 1721-1803
    Regarding an act to incorporate the Episcopal Church, separation of church and state.
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1785 March 7; 1p.; Pendleton, Edmund, 1721-1803
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1785 March 15; 3p.; Washington, George
    Ohio lands; Shawnees.
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee(?), 1785 March 16; 2p.; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves, marquis de, 1757-1834
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1785 April 18; 2p.; Pendleton, Edmund, 1721-1803
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1785 April 29; 3p.; Adams, John
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1785 June 22; 3p.; Washington, George
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1785 July 15; 4p.; Adams, John
    Critique of American policy toward Britain.
  - To "A Gentleman of Virginia", 1785 July 19; 3p.; Washington, George
    Regarding rights of navigation of the Mississippi River.
  - ALS to unidentified recipient, 1785 Aug. 22; 3p.; Washington, George
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1785 Sept. 6; 4p.; Adams, John
  - ALS to unidentified recipient, 1786 May 24; 3p.; Monroe, James, 1758-1831
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1787 Dec. 3; 2p.; Two page letter from Adams to Lee.; Adams, Samuel
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1789 July 2; 3p.; Chase, Samuel, 1741-1811
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1789 Feb. 9; 2p.; Gerry, Elbridge
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1789 April 11; 3p.; Sullivan, James
  - LS to Richard Henry Lee, 1789 April 22; 2p.; Adams, Samuel
  - LS to Richard Henry Lee, 1789 July 14; 2p.; Adams, Samuel
    Re: federal versus state balance.
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, 1789 Aug. 2; 2p.; Washington, George
  - LS to Richard Henry Lee, 1789 Aug. 24; 3p.; Adams, Samuel
  - LS to Richard Henry Lee, 1789 Aug. 24; 3p.; Adams, Samuel
  - ALS to Arthur Lee, 1790 Oct. 14; 1p.; Jones, William
  - ALS to Arthur Lee, 1790 Nov. 7; 1p.; Jones, William
  - ALS to Richard Henry Lee, Jr., 1823 Feb. 12; 3p.; Jay, John
    Memories of events of 1774.
  - Fortifications of Boston Neck by the British, ca.1775; 1 map, 39.5 x 32.1 cm; Unidentified
    The cartographer is thought to be John Trumball.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    Oversized.
    Other Finding Aids note
    Realms of Gold, 25 (1).